Guide to the Elizabeth Bishop Papers, circa 1880-2023 (bulk 1929-1979)
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
- SERIES I. CORRESPONDENCE
  - Letters from Elizabeth Bishop
    - To [Bowers], Aunt Grace, 1973; (9 letters, 7 postcards) (Folder 26.3)
    - To [Bowers], Aunt Grace, 1974; (7 letters, 13 postcards) (Folder 26.4)
    - To [Bowers], Aunt Grace, 1975; (7 letters, 6 postcards) (Folder 26.5)
    - To [Bowers], Aunt Grace, 1976; (9 letters, 2 postcards) (Folder 26.6)
    - To [Bowers], Aunt Grace, 1977; (2 letters) (Folder 26.7)
    - To [Bowers], Aunt Grace, undated; (24 postcards, 5 greeting cards) (Folder 26.8)
    - To [Bowers], Aunt Grace, undated; (14 letters) (Folder 26.9)
    - To Bowie, Dorothee, 1966; (6 letters, 5 postcards, 1 telegram) (Folder 27.1)
    - To Bowie, Dorothee, 1967; (9 letters, 3 postcards) (Folder 27.2)
    - To Bowie, Dorothee, 1968; (7 letters, 2 postcards) (Folder 27.3)
    - To Bowie, Dorothee, 1969; (3 letters, 3 postcards) (Folder 27.4)
    - To Bowie, Dorothee, 1970 Feb-Jul; (8 letters, 1 postcard) (Folder 27.5)
    - To Bowie, Dorothee, 1970 Aug-Nov; (9 letters, 3 postcards) (Folder 27.6)
    - To Bowie, Dorothee, 1970 Dec 7; (1 letter) (Folder 114.5)
    - To Bowie, Dorothee, 1971; (4 letters) (Folder 27.7)
    - To Bowie, Dorothee, 1971 Jun 7; (1 letter) (Folder 114.5)
    - To Bowie, Dorothee, 1972; (7 letters, 1 postcard, 1 Christmas card) (Folder 28.1)
    - To Bowie, Dorothee, 1973; (9 letters) (Folder 28.2)
    - To Bowie, Dorothee, 1974; (6 letters, 3 postcards) (Folder 28.3)
    - To Bowie, Dorothee, 1974 May-Jun; (3 letters, 1 postcard) (Folder 114.5)
    - To Bowie, Dorothee, 1975; (6 letters, 4 postcards) (Folder 28.4)
    - To Bowie, Dorothee, 1975 Jun 25; (1 postcard) (Folder 114.5)
    - To Bowie, Dorothee, 1976; (4 letters, 3 postcards) (Folder 28.5)
    - To Bowie, Dorothee, 1977; (1 postcard) (Folder 28.6)
    - To Bowie, Dorothee, 1978; (7 letters, 3 postcards) (Folder 28.7)
    - To Bowie, Dorothee, 1979; (8 letters, 3 postcards) (Folder 28.8)
    - To Bowie, Dorothee (presumably), undated; (List of books "to sell") (Folder 114.5)
    - To Brasil, Emanuel, 1967-1968; (6 letters, 4 postcards) (Folder 29.1)
    - To Brasil, Emanuel, 1969-1971; (8 letters, 2 greeting cards, 7 postcards, 1 letter from R. Cumming) (Folder 29.2)
    - To Brasil, Emanuel, 1972; (3 letters with 2 enclosures, 1 telegram, 3 postcards) (Folder 29.3)
    - To Brasil, Emanuel, 1973-1974; (8 letters, 3 postcards, 1 letter from Carlos Drummond de Andrade) (Folder 29.4)
    - To Brasil, Emanuel, 1975-1976, 1978, undated; (8 letters, 3 lists) (Folder 29.5)
    - To Brush, Marjorie Edwards, 1972 Nov 28; (1 carbon copy) (Folder 38.7)
    - To Carlile, Sandra McPherson and Henry, 1967-1978; (5 TLS, 4 postcards and 1 TLS to John Griffin) (Folder 117.31)
    - To Chittick, Victor L.O. and Edna, 1958-1979; (7 letters, 1 postcards, 1 greeting card) (Folder 29.6)
    - To Ciardi, John, 1955-1969; (7 letters, 1 change of address notification) (Folder 99.12)
    - To Crane, Louise, 1974-1979; (3 letters, 2 postcards) (Folder 114.3)
    - To Crane, Louise, 1967, 1971; (2 postcards) (Folder 127.5)
    - To De Jesus, Vitoria, 1975 Jul 12; (1 photocopied letter) (Folder 117.22)
    - To Estees, Sybil, 1976-1977; (8 letters) (Folder 29.7)
    - To Filho, Jose Barretto, 1967-1968; (4 letters) (Folder 117.23)
    - To Filho, Jose Barretto — 2 letters between Roxanne Cumming and Edna Wilborn re Portuguese translation, 1968; (2 letters) (Folder 117.23)
    - To Fisher, [Anna Helena], 1978 Jul 5; (1 carbon copy) (Folder 38.7)
    - To Foster, Ruth, 1947; (3 letters, 1 timeline, 3 sets of photocopies) (Folder 118.33)
    - To Flynn, Judith, 1934 Mar 22; (1 letter) (Folder 38.12)
    - To Frankenberg, Lloyd and Loren MacIver (d. 5/3/98), 1942-1948; (2 letters, 3 postcards) (Folder 29.8)
    - To Frankenberg, Lloyd and Loren MacIver, 1949 May-Jul; (2 letters, 4 postcards) (Folder 29.9)
    - To Frankenberg, Lloyd and Loren MacIver, 1949 Aug; (4 letters, 4 postcards, 2 telegrams) (Folder 29.10)
    - To Frankenberg, Lloyd and Loren MacIver, 1949 Oct-Dec; (4 letters, 8 postcards) (Folder 29.11)
    - To Frankenberg, Lloyd and Loren MacIver, 1950 Jan-Aug; (3 letters, 9 postcards, 2 telegrams) (Folder 29.12)
    - To Frankenberg, Lloyd and Loren MacIver, 1950 Sep-Dec; (6 letters, 3 postcards) (Folder 29.13)
    - To Frankenberg, Lloyd and Loren MacIver, 1951-1954; (7 letters, 2 postcards) (Folder 29.14)
    - To Frankenberg, Lloyd and Loren MacIver, 1955-1956; (9 letters, 1 postcard) (Folder 30.1)
    - To Frankenberg, Lloyd and Loren MacIver, 1957; (7 letters, 3 postcards) (Folder 30.2)
    - To Frankenberg, Lloyd and Loren MacIver, 1958; (8 letters) (Folder 30.3)
    - To Frankenberg, Lloyd and Loren MacIver, 1959; (6 letters, 1 postcard) (Folder 30.4)
    - To Frankenberg, Lloyd and Loren MacIver, 1960 Feb-Jun; (6 letters, 2 postcards) (Folder 30.5)
    - To Frankenberg, Lloyd and Loren MacIver, 1960 Aug-Nov; (4 letters) (Folder 30.6)
    - To Frankenberg, Lloyd and Loren MacIver, 1961; (12 letters) (Folder 30.7)
    - To Frankenberg, Lloyd and Loren MacIver, 1962; (6 letters, 2 postcards) (Folder 30.8)
    - To Frankenberg, Lloyd and Loren MacIver, 1963; (4 letters) (Folder 30.9)
    - To Frankenberg, Lloyd and Loren MacIver, 1964; (5 letters, 4 postcards, 1 press release) (Folder 30.10)
    - To Frankenberg, Lloyd and Loren MacIver, 1965-1966; (5 letters, 2 postcards) (Folder 31.1)
    - To Frankenberg, Lloyd and Loren MacIver, 1968-1969; (6 letters, 2 postcards) (Folder 31.2)
    - To Frankenberg, Lloyd and Loren MacIver, 1970-1971; (6 letters, 6 postcards) (Folder 31.3)
    - To Frankenberg, Lloyd and Loren MacIver, 1971 Jul-Dec; (3 letters, 7 postcards) (Folder 31.4)
    - To Frankenberg, Lloyd and Loren MacIver, 1972; (3 letters, 4 postcards) (Folder 31.5)
    - To Frankenberg, Lloyd and Loren MacIver, 1973-1974; (4 letters, 7 postcards) (Folder 31.6)
    - To Frankenberg, Lloyd and Loren MacIver, 1975-1976; (2 letters, 10 postcards) (Folder 31.7)
    - To Frankenberg, Lloyd and Loren MacIver, 1977-1978; (2 letters, 14 postcards) (Folder 31.8)
    - To Frankenberg, Lloyd and Loren MacIver, 1979; (1 letter, 5 postcards) (Folder 31.9)
    - To Frankenberg, Lloyd and Loren MacIver, undated; (1 brochure, 13 postcards) (Folder 31.10)
    - To Hanson, Pauline, 1950-1952; (21 letters, 1 fragment) (Folder 32.1)
    - To Hanson, Pauline, 1953-1954; (6 letters, 1 postcard) (Folder 32.2)
    - To Hanson, Pauline, 1955-1957; (13 letters) (Folder 32.3)
    - To Hanson, Pauline, 1958-1977, undated; (7 letters) (Folder 32.4)
    - To Hartley, Wesley S. [Bishop’s response typed on his letter], 1975 Feb 5; (1 letter) (Folder 38.7)
    - To Howard, Richard, 1979 Jun 25; (1 letter) (Folder 38.13)
    - To Howes, Barbara and Bill, 1954, 1963, 1970, 1975; (1 letter, 4 postcards) (Folder 114.1)
    - To Huck, Irvine, [1967]-1971; (1 letter, 1 postcard) (Folder 32.5)
    - To Laughlin, James, 1937-1939; (13 letters (photocopies)) (Folder 32.6)
    - To Laughlin, James, 1940-1949; (14 letters, 6 postcards (all photocopies)) (Folder 32.7)
    - To Leão, Rosalina Azevedo and Magú Costa Ribeiro, 1954, 1957, 1965-1969,, undated; (28 letters) (Folder 113.8)
    - To Leão, Rosalina Azevedo and Magú Costa Ribeiro, 1957, 1958, 1964, 1966, 1968, and undated; (15 postcards) (Folder 113.10)
    - To Leão, Rosalina Azevedo and Magú Costa Ribeiro, 1967; (3 telegrams (Folder 113.11)
    - To Littlefield, Lester, [1942?]; (1 postcard) (Folder 38.14)
    - To [Marshall?], [Margaret?] "Peggy,", 1952; (1 letter) (Folder 99.8)
    - To Mazzaro, Jerome, 1978; (1 letter) (Folder 99.9)
    - To McKinney [Mr. ?], 1978 Apr 28; (1 letter) (Folder 38.7)
    - To Meigs, Mary, 1970-1976, undated; (13 letters, 5 postcards, 10 TMS by Meigs) (Folder 32.9)
    - To Merrill, James, 1951-1969; (18 letters, 8 postcards, 1 change of address note) (Folder 33.1)
    - To Merrill, James, 1970-1971; (14 letters, 4 postcards) (Folder 33.2)
    - To Merrill, James, 1972-1973; (8 letters, 6 postcards) (Folder 33.3)
    - To Merrill, James, 1974-1975; (7 letters, 4 postcards) (Folder 33.4)
    - To Merrill, James, 1976-1977; (5 letters, 2 postcards) (Folder 33.5)
    - To Merrill, James, 1976-1979, undated; (9 letters, 10 postcards) (Folder 33.6)
    - To Methfessel, Alice, [1970 Dec] 29-30; (1 letter) (Folder 118.34)
    - To Methfessel, Alice, 1971 Feb 8-12; (3 letters, 3 postcards, 1 photograph) (Folder 114.29)
    - To Methfessel, Alice, [1971 Feb 13?]; (1 letter fragment, 1 ms) (Folder 114.30)
    - To Methfessel, Alice, [1971] Feb 13; (1 letter, 1 receipt, 1 clipping) (Folder 114.31)
    - To Methfessel, Alice, 1971 Feb 14-21; (5 letters) (Folder 114.32)
    - To Methfessel, Alice, 1971 Feb 22; (1 letter, 1 clipping, 2 photographs) (Folder 114.33)
    - To Methfessel, Alice, 1971 Feb 24-26; (2 letters, 1 postcard) (Folder 114.34)
    - To Methfessel, Alice, [1971] Feb 27; (1 letter fragment - originally enclosed with [23 mMrch 1971] letter from Elizabeth Bishop to AM]) (Folder 114.35)
    - To Methfessel, Alice, 1971 Mar 19-23; (4 letters) (Folder 114.36)
    - To Methfessel, Alice, [1971 Mar 23]; (1 letter, 1 ms - transcribed passage from Melanie Klein's Love, Guilt and Reparation) (Folder 114.37)
    - To Methfessel, Alice, [1971] Mar 24; (1 letter, 1 postcard) (Folder 114.38)
    - To Methfessel, Alice, 1971 Mar 25-30; (5 letters) (Folder 114.39)
    - To Methfessel, Alice, 1971 Mar 31; (1 letter) (Folder 114.40)
    - To Methfessel, Alice, 1971 Apr; (4 letters, 3 postcards, 1 telegram) (Folder 115.1)
    - To Methfessel, Alice, 1971 May; (3 letters, 1 postcard, 2 photographs) (Folder 115.2)
    - To Methfessel, Alice, [1971] Jun 30; (1 letter, 1 Do Not Disturb card) (Folder 115.3)
    - To Methfessel, Alice, 1971 Jul 2-6; (6 letters) (Folder 115.4)
    - To Methfessel, Alice, 1971 Jul 7-13; (5 letters) (Folder 115.5)
    - To Methfessel, Alice, 1971 Jul 16-20; (3 letters, 1 postcard, 4 annotated news clippings) (Folder 115.6)
    - To Methfessel, Alice, 1971 Aug 7; (1 letter) (Folder 115.7)
    - To Methfessel, Alice — "4 pm,", [Fall 1971?]; (1 letter) (Folder 118.35)
    - To Methfessel, Alice, 1972 Jun [18]; (1 letter) (Folder 115.8)
    - To Methfessel, Alice, [1972 Jun 19]; (1 letter, 1 postcard, 1 clipping, 1 note) (Folder 115.9)
    - To Methfessel, Alice, [1972] Jun [23?]; (1 letter) (Folder 115.10)
    - To Methfessel, Alice, 1972 Jun 25-30; (6 letters, 1 postcard) (Folder 115.11)
    - To Methfessel, Alice, 1972 [Jul 2]; (1 letter) (Folder 115.12)
    - To Methfessel, Alice, 1972 Jul 4; (1 letter, 1 clipping,1 1000 cruzeiros note) (Folder 115.13)
    - To Methfessel, Alice, 1972 Jul 5-8; (4 letters) (Folder 115.14)
    - To Methfessel, Alice, 1972 Jul 9-17; (5 letters, 1 postcard) (Folder 115.15)
    - To Methfessel, Alice, 1973 Mar 23-30; (4 letters) (Folder 118.36)
    - To Methfessel, Alice, [1973] Apr 20; (1 letter) (Folder 118.37)
    - To Methfessel, Alice, 1975 Jun 25; (1 letter) (Folder 118.38)
    - To Methfessel, Alice, 1975 Oct 8; (1 letter) (Folder 118.39)
    - To Methfessel, Alice, 1975 Dec 18; (1 letter) (Folder 118.40)
    - To Methfessel, Alice, 1976 Jan 15-16; (2 letters) (Folder 118.41)
    - To Methfessel, Alice — empty envelopes, (2 envelopes) (Folder 118.42)
    - [Draft of a telegram to Alice Methfessel?], Rio de Janeiro, undated; (1 note) (Folder 118.43)
    - To Mizener, Arthur, 1946; (1 letter) (Folder 99.10)
    - To Moore, Marianne, 1952, undated; (1 letter, 1 postcard) (Folder 33.7)
    - To Moore, Marianne, 1934-1970; (see photocopies of Marianne Moore Collection from the Rosenbach Museum and Library, 2 boxes)
    - To Muchnic, Helen, 1948, 1968-1974; (6 letters, 3 postcards) (Folder 33.8)
    - To Muchnic, Helen, 1977-1979; (12 letters, 3 postcards) (Folder 33.9)
    - To Muchnic, Helen from Alice Methfessel, 1977-1979; (10 letters, 4 postcards) (Folder 33.10)
    - To Mullen, [Miss ?], 1979 Jun 15; (1 carbon copy) (Folder 38.7)
    - To Muser, Frani Blough, 1928-1929; (4 letters) (Folder 34.1)
    - To Muser, Frani Blough, 1930 -1933; (11 letters, 1 postcard) (Folder 34.2)
    - To Muser, Frani Blough, 1934; (11 letters, 2 postcards) (Folder 34.3)
    - To Muser, Frani Blough, 1935; (3 letters, 2 postcards) (Folder 34.4)
    - To Muser, Frani Blough, 1936; (6 letters, 10 postcards, 2 telegrams) (Folder 34.5)
    - To Muser, Frani Blough, 1937; (8 letters, 4 postcards, 1 telegram) (Folder 34.6)
    - To Muser, Frani Blough, 1938-1939; (6 letters, 1 postcard) (Folder 34.7)
    - To Muser, Frani Blough, 1940-1941; (3 letters) (Folder 34.8)
    - To Muser, Frani Blough, 1962-1964; (4 letters, 2 postcards) (Folder 35.1)
    - To Muser, Frani Blough, 1965; (5 letters, 2 letters from Maya Osser) (Folder 35.2)
    - To Muser, Frani Blough, 1967-1968; (3 letters, 1 postcard) (Folder 35. 3)
    - To Muser, Frani Blough, 1969; (6 letters, 3 postcards, 1 telegram) (Folder 35.4)
    - To Muser, Frani Blough, 1970; (2 letters, 2 postcards) (Folder 35.5)
    - To Muser, Frani Blough, 1971; (5 letters, 6 postcards, 1 telegram) (Folder 35.6)
    - To Muser, Frani Blough, 1972-1973; (11 letters, 5 postcards) (Folder 35.7)
    - To Muser, Frani Blough, 1974-1975; (10 letters, 5 postcards) (Folder 35.8)
    - To Muser, Frani Blough, 1976-1977; (12 letters, 5 postcards) (Folder 35.9)
    - To Muser, Frani Blough, 1978-1979; (9 letters, 6 postcards) (Folder 35.10)
    - To Najila, [Doña ?], 1970 Aug 10; (1 letter) (Folder 38.7)
    - To Nemer, Linda [in Portuguese], 1970 Aug-Oct; (10 letters, 9 postcards) (Folder 36.1)
    - To Nemer, Linda [in Portuguese], 1970 Nov-Dec; (5 letters, 8 postcards) (Folder 36.2)
    - To Nemer, Linda [in Portuguese], 1971 Jan-Jun; (9 letters, 9 postcards) (Folder 36. 3)
    - To Nemer, Linda [in Portuguese], 1971 Jul-Sep; (4 letters, 4 postcards) (Folder 36.4)
    - To Nemer, Linda [in Portuguese], 1972-1976, undated; (7 letters, 6 postcards, 1 Christmas card) (Folder 36.5)
    - To Nemer, Linda [English translations], (20 letters, 3 postcards) (Folder 36.6)
    - To Nemer, Linda [English translations], (16 letters) (Folder 36.7)
    - To Nemer, Linda [English translations], (16 letters, 5 postcards) (Folder 36.8)
    - To Nemer, Linda [English translations], (13 letters, 4 postcards) (Folder 36.9)
    - To Orr, [Uncle] Irving, 1958 Dec 4; (1 card) (Folder 38.15)
    - To Page, Chester, 1972-1979; (12 letters) (Folder 127.4)
    - To Paz, Octavio, 1979; (1 letter (photocopy)) (Folder 37.1)
    - To Pereira, Estella Maria Ruy Barbosa Baptista, 1956, 1967-1969; (16 letters, 2 postcards) (Folder 99.1)
    - To Pereira, Estella Maria Ruy Barbosa Baptista, 1969 Feb 3; (1 letter) (Folder 113.9)
    - To Putnam, John, 1945 Oct 1; (1 letter) (Folder 114.7)
    - RIBEIRO, MAGÚ COSTA: see Leão, Rosalina Azevedo and Magú Costa Ribeiro
    - To Russell, Charlotte, circa 1939-1942; (11 letters) (Folder 127.16)
    - To [Russell], Jane [regarding copy 2 of the 1967 edition of Brazil], [approximately 1969]; (1 letter) (Folder 114.6)
    - To Sargent, Kay Orr [cousin], 1952-1955; (8 letters, 1 card) (Folder 99.2)
    - To Sargent, Kay Orr [cousin], 1956-1959; (11 letters) (Folder 99. 3)
    - To Sargent, Kay Orr [cousin], 1960-1961; (9 letters, 2 empty envelopes) (Folder 99.4)
    - To Sargent, Kay Orr [cousin], 1963-1966; (7 letters, 1 postcard) (Folder 99.5)
    - To Sargent, Kay Orr [cousin], 1967-1970; (6 letters, 4 empty envelopes) (Folder 99.6)
    - To Scott, Laurence, 1966-1967; (1 letter, 1 postcard) (Folder 99.11)
    - To Shapiro, David, [1973] Oct 12; (1 letter, draft) (Folder 38.16)
    - To Slonim, Ruth, 1966 Feb 5; (1 letter, 1 enclosure) (Folder 114.9)
    - To Soares, Lota de Macedo, 1960; (3 letters) (Folder 32.8)
    - To Soares, Lota de Macedo, 1960 Feb 20; (1 telegram) (Folder 118.44)
    - To Soares, Lota de Macedo, [1963 Mar 22]; (1 letter) (Folder 118.45)
    - To Soares, Lota de Macedo, [1964 Jun]; (1 letter) (Folder 118.46)
    - To Soares, Lota de Macedo, 1964 Jun 17-21; (3 letters, 1 postcard) (Folder 118.47)
    - To Soares, Lota de Macedo, 1964 Jun 22-30; (6 letters, 1 postcard) (Folder 118.48)
    - To Soares, Lota de Macedo, 1964 Jul 3-7; (2 letters, 1 telegram) (Folder 118.49)
    - To Soares, Lota de Macedo, 1964 Jul 10-20; (4 letters) (Folder 118.50)
    - To Soares, Lota de Macedo — empty envelopes, 1964 Jun-Jul; (3 envelopes) (Folder 118.51)
    - To [Soares, Lota de Macedo?] — valentine, undated; (1 greeting card) (Folder 118.52)
    - To Spicer, James, 1971 May-Jun; (2 letters, 1 postcard) (Folder 127.17)
    - To Staines, David, 1973-1974; (2 postcards) (Folder 115.19)
    - To Sternberg, Ricardo, 1974-1979; (8 letters, 3 postcards) (Folder 114.2)
    - To Summers, U. T. and Joseph, 1947-1954; (11 letters, 3 postcards, 1 published article) (Folder 37.2)
    - To Summers, U. T. and Joseph, 1955-1958; (14 letters, 3 postcards) (Folder 37. 3)
    - To Summers, U. T. and Joseph, 1959-1964; (21 letters, 4 postcards) (Folder 37.4)
    - To Summers, U. T. and Joseph, 1965-1973; (13 letters, 3 postcards) (Folder 37.5)
    - To Summers, U. T. and Joseph, 1978-1979; (3 letters and notes for memorial reading) (Folder 37.6)
    - To Summers, U. T. and Joseph, (7 envelopes and 4 photos) (Folder 37.7)
    - Bishop annotations for The Wine Cook Book (Folder 37.9)
    - To Sutherland, Phyllis, 1961-1974; (12 letters, 1 postcard) (Folder 38.1)
    - To Sutherland, Phyllis, 1975-1979; (12 letters, 2 postcards) (Folder 38.2)
    - To Sutherland, Phyllis, 1980; (1 letter, from Dalhousie University) (Folder 38. 3)
    - To Swenson, May, 1968, undated; (2 postcards) (Folder 38.4)
    - To Thomas, Harriet Tompkins, 1935-1936; (4 letters, 1 postcard) (Folder 38.5)
    - To Travisano, Thomas, 1979 Mar 2; (1 draft letter, torn and taped) (Folder 117.24)
    - To Wehr, Wesley, 1966-1972; (3 letters, 1 postcard) (Folder 38.6)
    - To Wehr, Wesley, 1967 Aug 11; (1 letter) (Folder 114.4)
    - To Wollf, Dr. Nathan S. written from Blythewood Sanitarium?], 1949 May 27; (1 postcard) (Folder 38.17)
    - To Yale College, Director of Admissions re: M. Ettinger, 1979 Jan 4; (1 carbon copy) (Folder 38.7)
    - To [ ? ], Bill [William Beckett? re: upcoming exam in Bishop's class], undated; (1 card, 1 note) (Folder 38.7)
    - To [ ? ], Bob, 1979 Apr 22; (1 carbon copy) (Folder 38.7)
    - To [ ? ], David, 1972 Dec 14; (1 letter) (Folder 38.7)
    - To [ ? ], Elizabeth (or Betty), 1979 Apr 9; (1 carbon copy) (Folder 38.7)
    - To [ ? ], Elodie, 1962 Dec 1; (1 letter) (Folder 113.9)
    - To [ ? ], Mary, [no year] Jul 17; (1 letter) (Folder 113.9)
    - To the Editor of 2° Caderno, 1965 Mar 5; (1 draft letter, 2 translated draft letters) (Folder 38.18)
    - [Change of Address Notification] for Bishop and Lota Soares, [approximately 1955] (Folder 38.19)
    - To [?] [Letter never sent re: review of Geography III], [1976?]; (1 carbon copy) (Folder 38.7)
    - To others [listed individually above], (7 carbon copies, 5 letters, 1 card, 1 note) (Folder 38.7)
  - Letters between others
    - Armstrong, Phyllis to Lloyd Frankenberg, 1949 May 17, undated; (1 postcard - removed from Frankenberg's review copy of North and South along with a TS copy of "Faustina," 1 MS copy of "Varick Street," and 1 clipping of "The Bight") (Folder 124.15)
    - Caffrey, Jefferson to Jose Eduardo de Macedo Soares, 1942 Dec 8; (1 letter) (Folder 117.25)
    - Calder, Alexander to Lota de Macedo Soares, [1964?] Jun 29; (1 postcard) (Folder 117.26)
    - Crane, Louis to Josephine Crane, undated; (2 letters) (Folder 127.6)
    - Cumming, Roxanne to Emanuel Brasil, 1969 Oct 27; (2 letters) (Folder 117.27)
    - Desbrisay to U.T. Summers, 1983; (2 letters) (Folder 37.8)
    - [Hutchinson?], "Aunt Charlotte" to Gertrude Bishop, 1911 Dec 22; (1 postcard) (Folder 117.28)
    - Moore, Marianne to Louise Crane, undated; (2 letters) (Folder 117.29)
    - Trindade, Paulo to James Spicer, 1971 Jun 7; (1 letter) (Folder 117.30)
- SERIES II. PROFESSIONAL CORRESPONDENCE, CONTRACTS, FINANCIAL STATEMENTS
  - Academy of American Poets, 1964-1978; (3 letters, 2 cc from Elizabeth Bishop) (Folder 39.1)
  - American Academy and Institute of Arts and Letters, 1976-1977 (Folder 122.21)
  - American Academy and Institute of Arts and Letters — Awards Committee minutes, 1975-1977 (Folder 39.2)
  - American Academy of Arts and Sciences — Certificate of membership, 1968 (Folder 107.5 (Oversize))
  - Antaeus/The Ecco Press, [1975?]-1979; (8 letters) (Folder 39.3)
  - Associated Writing Program, 1977; (1 letter fr. Bishop, draft and enclosure) (Folder 39.4)
  - Awards List, compiled by Poets and Writers, Inc., 1978 (Folder 122.22)
  - Books Abroad/Neustadt International Prize for Literature, 1976; (letters, drafts, miscellaneous material) (Folder 39.5)
  - Books Abroad/Neustadt International Prize for Literature, 1976-1978; (letters, drafts, miscellaneous material) (Folder 39.6)
  - Books Abroad/Neustadt International Prize for Literature, 1976; (award certificate) (Folder 107.1 (Oversize))
  - Brandt and Brandt, 1958-1973; (8 letters, royalty statements) (Folder 39.7)
  - Brandt and Brandt, 1972-1977; (2 letters, royalty statements) (Folder 122.23)
  - Brandt and Brandt — See also Contracts, Folder 44.1
  - BBC/David Cheshire, 1979; (l letter) (Folder 39.8)
  - Broadcast Music, Inc. — Royalties Statements, 1978-1979 (Folder 122.24)
  - Caedmon, 1956-1968; (4 letters from E. Bishop, contracts royalty statements) (Folder 39.9)
  - Chapelbrook Foundation, 1960; (1 letter 1 draft letter fr. E. Bishop to A. MacLeish 1 fragment) (Folder 39.10)
  - Chatto and Windus, 1967-1979; (7 letters) (Folder 39.11)
  - Cumming, Roxanne, 1967-1968; (1 invoice 3 reference letters fr. E. Bishop) (Folder 39.12)
  - Lucy Martin Donnelly Fellowship, 1951; (1 letter) (Folder 39.13)
  - Doubleday, 1948, 1973; (2 letters) (Folder 39.14)
  - Farrar, Straus and Giroux, 1967-1968; (Miscellaneous letters, enclosures, ccs from E. Bishop and R. Cumming) (Folder 40.1)
  - Farrar, Straus and Giroux, 1969, 1971 and 1976; (Miscellaneous letters, enclosures, ccs from E. Bishop and R. Cumming) (Folder 40.2)
  - Farrar, Straus and Giroux, 1977-1978; (Miscellaneous letters, enclosures, ccs from E. Bishop and R. Cumming) (Folder 40.3)
  - Farrar, Straus and Giroux, 1979 and [undated]; (Miscellaneous letters, enclosures, ccs from E. Bishop and R. Cumming) (Folder 40.4)
  - Farrar, Straus and Giroux, 1977 (Folder 123.1)
  - Farrar, Straus and Giroux — Permissions, 1968-1973 (Folder 123.2)
  - Farrar, Straus and Giroux — Royalties Statements, 1977-1979 (Folder 123.3)
  - Farrar, Straus and Giroux — See also Contracts, Folder 44.4
  - Freire, Paulo Rocha, 1979; (4 letters statements) (Folder 40.5)
  - Freire, Paulo Rocha and Mario A. Freire Neto — General, 1974-1976, undated (Folder 124.3)
  - Freire, Paulo Rocha and Mario A. Freire Neto — Statements, 1973-1977 (Folder 124.4)
  - David R. Godine, Inc., 1979; (7 letters) (Folder 40.6)
  - Guggenheim Fellowship, 1947-1978; (Applications, notice of award, correspondence, IRS regulations) (Folder 40.7)
  - Guggenheim Fellowship — Rosalind Wright recommendation, undated; (1 torn draft letter) (Folder 123.4)
  - Harvard University English Dept., 1970-1976; (9 letters l letter fr. E. Bishop, l letter about E. Bishop, 4 assignment sheets) (Folder 40.8)
  - Harvard Univ. Library, 1973; (Correspondence re: Lowell collection at Harvard, purchase agreement, memo of agreement) (Folder 40.9)
  - Honorary degree: Adelphi University, 1977; (reduced size copy) (Folder 40.10)
  - Honorary degree: Adelphi University, 1977; (original) (Folder 97.3)
  - Honorary degree: Amherst College, 1979 (Folder 40.10)
  - Honorary degree: Brandeis University, 1978; (reduced size copy) (Folder 40.10)
  - Honorary degree: Brandeis University, 1978; (original) (Folder 106.4)